Guide to the Arnold Sundgaard papers, 1925-1988
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
- Series 6: Programs and Posters, 1925-1988; (boxes 22-29, oversize folder)
  - Programs - M, 1939-1974 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    Madam, Will You Walk; Mademoiselle Colombe; Maggie Flynn; The Magic Show; Malcolm; Mame; The Man in the Glass Booth; Man of La Mancha; Marcel Marceau; Macbeth; The Madwoman of Chaillot; Maggie; The Magic and the Loss; Make a Wish; Mamba's Daughters; APA at the Phoenix fundraising pamphlet; A Man for all Seasons; Marathon '33.
  - Programs - M, 1947-1978 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    Martha Graham; Medea; The Member of the Wedding; Mark Twain Tonight; Antony and Cleopatra; The Matchmaker; Me and Juliet; Metropolitan Opera; A Midsummer Night's Dream; The Mighty Gents; Middle of the Night; Milk and Honey; The Milk Train Doesn't Stop Here Anymore; Mineola; The Miracle Worker.
  - Programs - M, 1947-1973 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Miss Lonelyhearts; Molly; Moonchildren; Morning, Noon and Night; The Mother of us all; Much Ado About Nothing; Mixed Doubles; My Fair Lady; My 3 Angels; Misalliance; Mister Johnson; Monique; A Month in the Country; The Moon is Blue; The Most Happy Fella; Mother Courage and her Children; Mrs. McThing; The Music Man; My Fair Lady.
  - Programs - miscellaneous, 1935-1967 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    Forests of the Night (Dublin); Trouble in Tahiti / Down in the Valley; The Great Campaign; The Greenfield Christmas Tree; Kittiwake Island; Kilgo Run; Cumberland Fair; Giants in the Earth; The Great Campaign; Little Orchestra Society; Lemonade Opera; The Lowland Sea; The Playboy of the Western World; Pygmalion; On Hemlock Brook; The Neighborhood Playhouse School of the Theatre presents its 25th anniversary program; National Theatre Conference; The Old Vic Theatre Company; Habimah; The Great Western Union; The Annual Spring Musicale at George School; Of Love Remembered.
  - Programs - miscellaneous, 1935-1972 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    Rhapsody; The First Crocus; Everywhere I Roam; Kittiwake Island; Promised Valley; The Sixteenth Annual Dance Concert of the Steffi Nossen School; Spring Opera Night; This Fallow Ground; The Ramapo Lyric Festival; Town Hall - The Little Orchestra Society, Inc.; Virginia Overture Hi Song Daisy Lee; The Waldorf School Spring Festival; Forests of the Night performed at the Weathervane Community Playhouse; Cumberland Fair; Children's Theatre at the 92nd St. YM and YWHA; Central High School Vocal Music Department - Festival of Contemporary Music; University of Denver - Sunday Excursion and Down in the Valley; Canterbury Choral Society - Down in the Valley; Roslyn High School - Americana; Fifth annual conference on American Opera by the Columbia University Student Council; Beatrice and Benedict; Of Love Remembered; Southern Theatre; Spirochete; C.W. Post College - The First Intercollegiate Playwriting Festival; Gallantry.
  - Programs - miscellaneous, 1948-1973 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    Two issues of Opera News; Occidental College Music Department - A Festival of Twentieth Century Music; Dublin University Players - Vacant Lot; Beatrice and Benedict; The Orchestra of America; Stadium Concerts Review; Nobody's Earnest.
  - Programs - miscellaneous, 1959-1973 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    Nobody's Earnest; Close-Up: A collection of photographs by L. Arnold Weissberger publication; Promised Valley; Forests of the Night; An Evening of Contemporary American Opera; Giants in the Earth.
  - Programs - N, 1948-1968 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    The National Council of the Metropolitan Opera Association Regional Auditions Finals; The Neighborhood Playhouse School of the Theatre; The New Dance Group; New York City Ballet; The New York City Center Light Opera Company; New York City Center of Music and Drama; New York City Opera Company; New York City Theatre Company; No Time for Sergeants; The Natural Look; Nature of the Crime; New Faces of 1962; The New Music Hall of Israel; New York State Theater - Annie Get Your Gun; Next Time I'll Sing to You; Nikolais Dance Theatre; No, No, Nanette; No Place to be Somebody; No Time for Sergeants.
  - Programs - N, 1955-1972 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    Not Now, Darling; No Time for Sergeants; Narrow Road to the Deep North; New York State Theater - Kind Lear.
  - Programs - O, 1946-1977 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    Oakdale musical theatre; The Odd Couple; Of Love Remembered; Oh What a Lovely War; Old Times; Oliver!; On a Clear Day You Can See Forever; Ondine; On Stage; Orpheus Descending; The Observer film exhibition program; Oh Men! Oh Women!; Oklahoma; Old Acquaintance; Ondine; One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest; Oh Dad, Poor Dad, Mamma's Hung You in the Closet and I'm Feelin' so Sad; On the Town; On Whitman Avenue; Otherwise Engaged.
  - Programs - O, 1950; 1970 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    Oxford University Players - The Alchemist King Lear; Operation Sidewinder.
  - Programs - P, 1951-1978 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    Philemon; Paint Your Wagon; Pal Joey; Park; Peg; Lord Pengo; A Penny for a Song; Philadelphia, Here I Come!; Photo Finish; The Physicists; Pacific Overtures; A Passage to India; The Passion of Josef D.; A Patriot for Me; The Paul Taylor Dance Company; Peter Pan.
  - Programs - P, 1939-1978 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    Pilobolus dance theatre; The Pirates of Penzance; Players; The Playroom; Plaza Suite; Picnic; The Pinter Plays - The Dumbwaiter and the Collection; Paint Your Wagon; Plain and Fancy; The Playhouse Company; The Plumstead Playhouse - Our Town; The Ponder Heart; Poor Richard; Porgy and Bess; Portrait of a Queen; The Prescott Proposals; King Lear at Brandeis University; The Price.
  - Programs - P, 1945-1970 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    The Prime of Miss Jean Brodie; The Prescott Proposals; Private Lives; Promenade; Purlie; Pygmalion; Purple Dust; The Prime of Miss Jean Brodie; The Potting Shed; The Private Ear and the Public Eye; The Promise; Promises, Promises.
  - Programs - R, 1945-1977 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    The Rainmaker; The Rape of Lucretia; The Rat Race; The Red Mill; The Rehearsal; The Reluctant Debutante; Repertory Theater of Lincoln Center; The Right Honourable Gentleman; The Robber Bridegroom; Rabelais; A Raisin in the Sun; The Real Inspector Hound After Magritte; Red Roses for Me; The Remarkable Mr. Pennypacker; Rhinoceros; Ring Round the Moon; The Repertory Theatre of Lincoln Center - Yerma.
  - Programs - R, 1938-1976 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    Ceremonial Tribute to Robert Emmet Sherwood (at ANTA Theatre); Romulus; Rosa; The Rose Tattoo; Ross; The Royal Family; Ruth Draper; The Rockland Foundation; Rooms; The Rose Tattoo; The Rothschilds; The Royal Hunt of the Sun; The Runner Stumbles; The Remarkable Mr. Pennypacker.
  - Programs - S, 1951-1977 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    Sandhog; Saint Joan; Say Darling; A Scent of Flowers; The School for Scandal; Serjeant Musgrave's Dance; Seventeen; The Seven Year Itch; 1776; Shakespeare in Harlem; She Loves Me; Shenandoah; Shelter; The Saint of Bleecker Street; Salvation; The School for Wives; Seascape; Second Threshold; The Secret Affairs of Mildred Wild; Shadow of a Star; The Shadow Box; Sheep on the Runway; Sherlock Holmes; Shakespeare Festival.
  - Programs - S, 1939-1977 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    Show Boat; Shoestring Revue; The Sign in Sidney Brustein's Window; Side by Side by Sondheim; Skyscraper; Sleuth; The Soldier; South Pacific; Stars in Your Eyes; The Sleepers' Den; Silk Stockings; Sing Me No Lullaby; Slapstick Tragedy; Slow Dance on the Killing Ground; Soldiers; Spofford; Staircase.
  - Programs - S, 1947-1972 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    The Star Spangled Girl; Sticks and Bones; Story Theatre; Stop the World I Want to Get Off; The Sudden and Accidental Re-Education of Horse Johnson; The Subject was Roses; Sugar; The Sunshine Boys; Sweet Bird of Youth; A Streetcar Named Desire; Street Scene; Sunday Breakfast; Sunrise at Campobello; The Square Root of Wonderful; Sweet Charity; Summertree.
  - Programs - T, 1948-1976 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    Tamburlaine the Great; The Taming of the Shrew; A Taste of Honey; Tea and Sympathy; The Teahouse of the August Moon; That Championship Season; Theives Carnival; Third Person; The Threepenny Opera; Tchin-Tchin; Telemachus Clay; A Temporary Island; The Tenth Man; A Texas Trilogy; Theater 1969; 3 for Tonight.
  - Programs - T, 1951-1975 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    Ti-Coo; Tiger at the Gates; The Time of the Cuckoo; Top Banana; Touchstone; Traveler without Luggage; Travesties; Treemonisha; The Trial of Lee Harvey Oswald; Two by Two; The Actors Studio Theatre productions 1963-1964; Those That Play the Clowns; Tiger Tiger Burning Bright; Tiny Alice; Town Hall; A Tree Grows in Brooklyn; Time Limit!; The Trip to Bountiful; Two on the Aisle; Two Gentlemen of Verona
  - Programs - Under Milk Wood to U.S.A., 1957-1967 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    Under Milk Wood; Ulysses; The Unknown Soldier and His Wife; U.S.A.
  - Programs - V, 1955-1975 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    Very Good Eddie; Vivat! Vivat Regina!; The Visit; Visit to a Small Planet; Via Galactica; A View from the Bridge.
  - Programs - W, 1947-1970 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    Waiting for Godot; Wait a Minim!; The Way of the World; West Side Story; Who am I?; Who to Love; Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf?; Wait Until Dark; Walking Happy; Where's Charley?; The Whole World Over; Will Success Spoil Rock Hunter?; Wilson in the Promise Land; The Winslow Boy; Witness for the Prosecution; The World of Gunter Grass; The Secret Life of Walter Mitty.
  - Programs - Y to Z, 1931-1969 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    The Zulu and the Zayda; The Young and Fair; Zorba; Your Own Thing; You Know I Can't Hear You When the Water's Running; You're a Good Man Charlie Brown; Ziegfeld Follies of 1931.
  - Promised Valley poster, circa 1960s-1970s (Oversize folder)
  - Promised Valley programs, 1947-1972 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Promised Valley programs, 1958-1968 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Promised Valley, Utah Centennial programs, 1947-1948 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    Promised Valley; The Great Campaign; Theatre Arts magazine (June 1947); Utah Centennial; Utah Symphony Orchestra.
  - Rhapsody programs, November 6, 1944 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Sunday Excursion program, 1950s (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - This Fallow Ground program, 1935 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - The Truth About Windmills programs, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Winnie (programs and playscript), 1988 (Box 29, Folder 10)
- Series 7: Writings, Reviews, Publications, 1933-1988; (boxes 29-37, 43-44)
  Series 7: Writings, Reviews, Publications (1933-1988) is arranged alphabetically by title and includes writings by Sundgaard that are not scripts. The writings include drafts, outlines, articles, essays, and short stories. Both unpublished and published material is included. There are some books. Also present is research material created by Sundgaard for different projects. One project was a syphilis related research project for a possible book that Sundgaard undertook with O.C. Wenger. Another project represented is research of deafness conducted by Sundgaard in Hermann, Missouri.
  - All is Calm, undated (Box 29, Folder 11)
    Short story published by Norske Tidende of Brooklyn.
  - An Axe, an Apple, and a Buckskin Jacket book, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - An Axe, an Apple, and a Buckskin Jacket (children's book and lyrics), 1956-1970 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - An Axe, an Apple and a Buckskin Jacket, December 1957 (Oversize 44)
    Article in Living magazine.
  - The Anvil (7), 1933-1935 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Ballet, 1939; 1942 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    John Brown for Erich Hawkins; Forty-Second Street.
  - The Blessing of Dreams (short story, formerly "Eleanor"), undated (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Buried Treasures in Louisiana; Cemeteries (two articles), 1939-1940 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    Written for the Federal Writers' Project New Orleans.
  - Butternut and Peanut in New York (children's story), 1977 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - A Child is Born, circa 1958 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    Text for film written with and for Anton Refregier.
  - Children's songs, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - (Deafness research) Carl Smith trip to Missouri (1 of 2), 1966-1967 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - (Deafness research) Carl Smith trip to Missouri (2 of 2), 1967 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    Correspondence, ephemera on Hermann, Missouri.
  - (Deafness research) Journal of a journey to Hermann, Missouri, circa 1967 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    Report written for Dr. Edna Levine of New York University and deafness research. Includes photographs.
  - Drama 109 final exam at Hofstra University, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Eleanor (short story, aka "The Blessing of Dreams"), 1973 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Elgin Tubbs (short story), undated (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Free World, September 1945 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    "Postwar Relaxation, a Story" article by Sundgaard.
  - Free World, October 1945; January 1946 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    Articles "The Realtors" and "The Lesson of the Potato".
  - Short stories published in Free World Magazine, undated (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Freedom: The Divine Obligation, 1948 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    Speech written for Lyndon B. Johnson in 1948, at the request of Buck Hood, editor of Austin "Item". It was recorded and broadcast over cotton fields from a helicopter.
  - Galileo (recorded drama), May 6, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - A Garland of Children's Songs (lyrics), 1976 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    Unpublished, music by Alec Wilder.
  - George Washington, 1939 (Box 30, Folder 15)
    Scenario for a film commissioned by Jed Harris.
  - George Washington, 1939 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - The Gypsies of Lillebakken (short story), 1962 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Bill (Otto) Harbach Project (cassette tapes), 1972-1973 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    Cassette recording of interview with Rudolph Friml, aged 93, made in Hollywood July 24, 1973. He talked of Otto Harbach and his career in the theatre.
  - Bill (Otto) Harbach Project, 1972-1973 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - How Lovely is Christmas (treatment for a television film), 1966 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Jazz: Hot and Cold (article for the Atlantic Monthly), 1955 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Jethro's Difficult Dinosaur book (children's story), 1977 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Jethro's Difficult Dinosaur (children's story), 1977 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Journal (kept at various times through the years), 1940-1967 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Ken (New Yorker article), 1959 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - The Lamb and the Butterfly (children's book proof), 1988 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Das Lämmlein und der Schmetterling (The Lamb and the Butterfly) published book, 1989 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - The Librettist (photocopy), November 1961 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    Article published in International Musician "Opera in America".
  - Lyrics (various unpublished), 1946-1968 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript, January, June 1934 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript, August-December 1934 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Manuscript, February-June 1935 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript, August 1935-April 1936 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Manuscript, June, October 1936 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Meet Jack Appleknocker (book), by Sundgaard and Sheila White Samton, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - The Miracle of Growth (book manuscript), 1951 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - The Miracle of Growth (two books), 1950, 1967 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Miss Ruddy (short story), undated (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Money (New Yorker article), 1973 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - The New Yorker, January 7, 1939 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    Issue of The New Yorker containing a review for "Everywhere I Roam".
  - The New Yorker, 1959-1973 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    Three issues of The New Yorker containing the articles "Reruns of the Mind", "Money", and "Ken".
  - O.C. Wenger scrapbook on Hot Springs Arkansas (1 of 5), 1939 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    During 1939 Sundgaard was working with the Writer's Project in Louisiana and Harper's had asked him to do a book about O.C. Wenger, USPHS chief who was campaigner against syphilis. Because of disagreements with Wenger about what form the book should take i.e., fiction vs. documentary, it was never written.
  - Health program Nogales, Mexico (confidential report) (2 of 5), 1940-1942 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Clinic recollections by O.C. Wenger (3 of 5), circa 1939-1942 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - O.C. Wenger (correspondence; chapter notes) (4 of 5), 1940-1941 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - O.C. Wenger (chapter notes typed and handwritten) (5 of 5), circa 1940s (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Original folder for the O.C. Wenger material, circa 1940s (Oversize 43)
  - Partisan Review, May-August 1952 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - People's Names and People's Faces (essay), undated (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Poems (various unpublished poetry), undated (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Portrait of the Librettist as a Silent Composer (photocopy, article), undated (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Publications - books, 1941-1958 (Box 34)
    "Jazz Hot and Cold" in Modern American Reader; "Equinox" in The Best One Act Plays of 1941; "Mid-Passage" in The Best One Act Plays of 1943; "The Picnic" in the Best One Act Plays of 1944; "Virginia Overture" in American Scenes.
  - Publications - magazine articles, 1939-1980 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    About Unesco; "Footsteps of Greatness...along the Lincoln Heritage Trail" in Vista; "Writing with Kurt Weill" in The Dramatists Guild Quarterly; New Masses.
  - Publications - magazine articles, 1955-1964 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    "Gallantry" review in Time and The New Yorker; Sundgaard featured in a survey in the Saturday Review; "Jazz Hot and Cold" in The Atlantic; "The Librettist - Secret Service Man" in International Musician.
  - Publications - journals, 1934-1943 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    The New Talent; Story; Accent; Icarus; Medallion (includes art work by Will Eisner).
  - Publications - journals, 1934-1935 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    Two issues of Manuscript; The New Talent; The Lance.
  - Publications - journals, 1934-1965 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    Story; three issues of Voices: A Journal of Poetry; Scope; author's copy of The New Talent.
  - Publications - journals, 1946; 1963 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    Voices: A Journal of Poetry; Everybody's Digest.
  - Reruns of the Mind (New Yorker article), 1973-1976 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Short stories, undated (Box 35, Folder 8)
    Indian Johnny; Autumn of a Virgin; Will You Please Let Me Tell the Story!
  - Short stories, 1959 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    Tury; The Invader.
  - Short stories, undated (Box 36, Folder 2)
    The Gun; The Apple Tree; Elgin Tubbs; Beckley and his Uncle Hamp; Journey to Duluth.
  - Short stories, undated (Box 36, Folder 3)
    I am Strong as a Horse; The Drifter; The Two of us in Texas; Hot Air, Fiddlesticks and Baloney.
  - Short stories, undated (Box 36, Folder 4)
    The Skerry Island Country Store; The Blessing of Dreams; Swimming to Damascus; A Child is Born.
  - Short stories, undated (Box 36, Folder 5)
    Tramp, Tramp, Tramp; Rasmus and the Flying Viking; The White City; The Singer; Change at Jamaica; A Lost Identity.
  - The Skerry Island Country Store (short story), undated (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Song parts (scraps of songs), 1968 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - A Sufficiency of Rain (short story), undated (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Swimming to Damascus (short story), January 29, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Theatre Arts magazine, July 1933; February 1936 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Theatre Arts magazine, February - March 1939 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Theatre Arts magazine, June 1947 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Utah Centennial source book, undated (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Weill-Lenya exhibit, 1976-1977 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Kurt Weill newsletter, 1959-1990 (Box 37, Folder 3)
- Series 8: Audio Recordings, 1955-1980s; (boxes 38-41)
  Series 8: Audio Recordings (1955-1980s) is arranged by size and consists of four boxes that include audio cassette tapes, reel-to-reel audio recordings, and vinyl records. The material includes recordings from productions or songs that Sundgaard wrote, and records featuring Sundgaard's children's books.
  - 5" and 7" Reel-to-reel audio tapes, 1955-1977 (Box 38)
    "Noa Noa" and other songs from musical of Gauguin based on Agee film script, lyrics by Sundgaard, music by D.K. Lee; Chet Baker interview; Maurice Jarre playing piano for Montparnasse music; Montparnasse first version; Montparnasse second version; Michel Legrand singing possible songs for Montparnasse (April 1970); Michel Legrand Montparnasse song ideas; University of North Dakota - Giants in the Earth act I; Giants in the Earth act II; Giants in the Earth act III; The Truth About Windmills - orchestra reading of score; The Truth About Windmills - tape made from performances at Avon, New York October 1973; Kittiwake Island; unlabeled, unboxed 7".
  - 5" and 7" Reel-to-reel audio tapes, 1958-1973 (Box 39)
    Montparnasse - music by Maurice Jarre, lyrics by Arnold Sundgaard; Gallantry at Columbia University Open Workshop; Buddy Biloxi re-recorded at CBS (1973) jazz musical; Forests of the Night at Gate Theatre in Dublin (1965); Nobody's Earnest demo.
  - Audio recordings, circa 1970s (Box 40)
    Contains 11 cassette tapes and two 3" reel to reel tapes. Tapes contain recordings of the Brigham soundtrack, The Sun and the Moon, Chet Baker, Alec Wilder suite no. 2, Kittiwake Island, eulogy to Robert Porterfield and the Tony awards, Truth About Windmills, Eddie Sauter and O Wonderous Earth, Montparnasse, various songs written by Sundgaard.
  - Vinyl record albums, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 41)
    An Axe, an Apple, and a Buckskin Jacket: A Christmas Story; Columbia University Bicentennial Album; Songs of the South; Bing Crosby tells and sings How Lovely is Christmas; Young Abe Lincoln; Brigham; Down in the Valley; How Lovely is Christmas.